ROBERT DUNNE

I am a highly motivated individual with a passion for sports journalism, social media and data analysis. I am meticulous in detail and tenacious, persistent and creative in my work. I am a resourceful researcher, writer and reporter with in-depth knowledge of new technology and working online.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sports Reporter and Translator

October 2016 - Present



- > Responsible for the running of AS English's social media including Twitter, Facebook and EchoBox.
- > Translating articles written by Spanish colleagues and ensuring facts and reporting are correct in the process.
- > Writing articles that include breaking news, features, profiles, match reports, previews and player ratings.
- > Keeping up with NFL, NBA, the Olympics, cycling, golf, tennis and creating content on all the biggest sports news.

Digital Sports Reporter

February 2018 - December 2018



- > Responsible for writing breaking news stories fast and to the highest quality for ESPNFC's website.
- > Pitching weekly blog posts that were both insighful and of the highest written quality.
- > Wacthing Real Madrid games and both reporting on them and assessing player performance through a ratings system.
- Liaising with site managers to ensure the website was up to date with the latest news and information.

Sports Commentator

January 2018 - December 2018



- > Commentating on Real Madrid football games from under 8's through the ranks at the club.
- > Live basketball commentatory on a host of Real Madrid basketball games in their famous basketball academy.
- > Editing footage of football and basketball games into highlights packages using Adobe Premiere Pro.
- > Working with our production team to ensure we were on top of team news and injuries.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

+34633400063

Calle Alaro 4,
Portal 1, 3D, Madrid

@ robbiejdunne@gmail.com

@robbiejdunne

QUALIFICATIONS

Diploma in Adobe Design Suite International Academy of Computer Training (Dublin, 2013)

Certificate in Spanish Language AIL (Madrid, Spain)

EDUCATION

BA Hons Degree in Media Production Management

Dublin College University September 2013 - April 2016

Fetac Level 6 in Sport and Exercise Psychology

Portobello Institute, Dublin February 2015 - May 2015

Higher Certificate in Computing

National College of Ireland, Dublin May 2003 - 2005

Higher National Diploma in Journalism

Ballyfermot College, Dublin September 2013 - 2015

Masters in Science in Data Analysis

National College of Ireland, Dublin (Online) 2020 - Present

REFERENCES

Available upon request.